## **Marco Catapano**

## Software Engineer

7+ years of experience focused in backend application development. I spent these years with the intent of getting continuously better in software engineering. I have always had and I still have curiosity towards languages in order to improve everyday; learning is a never ending process, especially in IT.

## About me

- ★ via Modenese 5, 51100 Pistoia (PT)
- **J** +39 3468772332
- marco.catapano.93@gmail.com
- catapano-marco@mail.com
- **4** 12/05/1993
- Personal Website

## **Experience**

current - 2022/05	Engineer II @ Trade Republic  Develop and extend BE µservices across multiple atoms Participating in technical interviews Help in shaping new developments by writing RFCs and other documentation Tech: Kotlin, Spring, VertX, GH Actions, ScyllaDB, Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, k8s, Datadog, AWS
2022/04 - 2021/05	Software Engineer @ Prima Assicurazioni  Develop FE and BE of the Agents' platform Tech: Rust, Docker, Elm, GraphQL, k8s, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Datadog
2021/05 - 2018/09	Software Engineer @ Extra Red     Develop Apache Camel routes and Spring REST services     DevOps engineering with OCP 3.x and Jenkins     Tech: Camel, Spring, Jenkins, OCP, Docker, Java8+, GitLab, RDBMS, ActiveMQ
2018/05 - 2016/09	Backend Developer @ M.E.T.A. Srl     Develop features in digital publishing back-ends     Extending websites of cultural authorities     Tech: PHP, MySQL, Solr, Git, GitLab, Bash
2016/08 - 2015/12	Backend Developer @ Siter Srl  Extend company main product either by changing the codebase or by creating external executables (e.g. SOAP consumers, IMAP desktop apps, etc.)  Tech: VB6, C#, Java 7, .NET 4, RDBMS
2015/10 - 2015/07	Internship @ Siter SrI  Develop a SOAP service and consumer for the company's main product DB Tech: VB6, C#, Java 7, .NET 4, RDBMS

## Misc.

In compliance with the GDPR and Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003, I hereby authorize the recipient of this document to use and process my personal details for the purpose of recruiting and selecting staff and I confirm to be informed of my rights in accordance to art. 7 of the above mentioned Decree.

## **Tech skills**

## Languages

Kotlin, Java, C#, Rust, VB, PHP Basic knowledge: Elm, Python, Golang, sh, F#, C, JS

#### Frameworks

Spring, VertX, Quarkus, Apache Camel, .NET Core, Actix Web

#### Tools

Maven, Gradle, NuGet, Cargo, Pip, Git, Docker, IntelliJ IDEA, VSCode, Visual Studio, Insomnia, Postman, Paw

### **Platforms**

OCP, Kubernetes, AWS, EAP, GitHub, GitLab, Quay.io, Datadog, Jira, Terraform, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Elasticsearch, ScyllaDB, Terraform, SonarCloud, RabbitMQ, ActiveMQ, JBoss Fuse

## Spoken languages

Italian: native English: B2+

## **Education**

## Bachelor's Degree in CompSci

## @ University of Pisa

**Score:** 110/110 - with honours **Subjects:** algorithms, data structures, FP, OOP, basic math, formal languages, RDBMS, computer arch, networks

# Business, Accounting, Programming ("Mercurio" project)

## @ I.I.S.S. Antonio Pesenti

Score: 100/100 - no honours Subjects: economics, applied math, IT